A Guide to the Henry Luce Foundation records, Clare Boothe Luce Designated Institution Files FA1855
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation records, Clare Boothe Luce Designated Institution Files
1988-2022
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation
FA1855
10.63 Cubic Feet 28 letter document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Clare Boothe Luce Designated Institution Files contain grant files for designated (also referred to as "invited") institutions. These institutions and universities were selected by Clare Boothe Luce to receive financial support in perpetuity.
Arrangement
As received.
Women in engineering -- United States; Women in science; Women in mathematics
- Boston University, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Boston University, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Boston University, 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Boston University, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Boston University, 2007-2012 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Colby College, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Colby College, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Colby College, 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Colby College, 2003-2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Colby College, 2007-2012 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
- Creighton University, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
- Creighton University, 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Creighton University, 1997-2002 (Box 4, Folder 15-17)
- Creighton University, 2003-2006 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
- Creighton University, 2007-2012 (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
- Fordham University, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Fordham University, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Fordham University, 1997-2002 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Fordham University, 2003-2006 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Fordham University, 2007-2012 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Georgetown University, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Georgetown University, 1993-1996 (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
- Georgetown University, 1997-2002 (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
- Georgetown University, 2003-2006 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Georgetown University, 2007-2012 (Box 7, Folder 33-34)
- Marymount University, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Marymount University, 1993-1996 (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Marymount University, 1997-2002 (Box 8, Folder 37)
- Marymount University, 2003-2006 (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Marymount University, 2007-2012 (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Mount Holyoke College, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 40)
- Mount Holyoke College, 1993-1996 (Box 9, Folder 41)
- Mount Holyoke College, 1997-2002 (Box 9, Folder 42-43)
- Mount Holyoke College, 2003-2006 (Box 9, Folder 44)
- Mount Holyoke College, 2007-2012 (Box 9, Folder 45-46)
- St. John's University, 1990-1992 (Box 10, Folder 47)
- St. John's University, 1993-1996 (Box 10, Folder 48)
- St. John's University, 1997-2002 (Box 10, Folder 49)
- St. John's University, 2003-2006 (Box 10, Folder 50)
- St. John's University, 2007-2012 (Box 10, Folder 51)
- Santa Clara University, 1988-1992 (Box 11, Folder 52)
- Santa Clara University, 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 53)
- Santa Clara University, 1997-2002 (Box 11, Folder 54)
- Santa Clara University, 2003-2006 (Box 11, Folder 55)
- Santa Clara University, 2007-2012 (Box 11, Folder 56)
- Seton Hall University, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 57)
- Seton Hall University, 1993-1996 (Box 12, Folder 58)
- Seton Hall University, 1997-2002 (Box 12, Folder 59)
- Seton Hall University, 2003-2006 (Box 12, Folder 60)
- Seton Hall University, 2007-2012 (Box 12, Folder 61)
- Trinity Washington University (Trinity College), 1989-1992 (Box 12, Folder 62-63)
- Trinity Washington University (Trinity College), 1993-1996 (Box 13, Folder 64)
- Trinity Washington University (Trinity College), 1997-2002 (Box 13, Folder 65)
- Trinity Washington University (Trinity College), 2003-2006 (Box 13, Folder 66)
- Trinity Washington University (Trinity College), 2007-2012 (Box 13, Folder 67)
- University of Notre Dame, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 68)
- University of Notre Dame, 1993-1996 (Box 13, Folder 69)
- University of Notre Dame, 1997-2002 (Box 14, Folder 70-71)
- University of Notre Dame, 2003-2006 (Box 14, Folder 72)
- University of Notre Dame, 2007-2012 (Box 14, Folder 73)
- Villanova Preparatory School, 1988-1992 (Box 14, Folder 74)
- Villanova Preparatory School, 1993-1996 (Box 14, Folder 75)
- Villanova Preparatory School, 1997-2002 (Box 14, Folder 76)
- Villanova Preparatory School, 2003-2006 (Box 15, Folder 77)
- Villanova Preparatory School, 2007-2012 (Box 15, Folder 78)
- Mundelein College, 1988-1990 (Box 15, Folder 79)
- Mundelein College, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 80)
- Agnes Scott College, 2006-2012 (Box 15, Folder 81-82)
- Boston College, 2004-2013 (Box 15, Folder 83)
- Bowdoin College, 2008-2017 (Box 16, Folder 84)
- Bryn Mawr College, 2006-2011 (Box 16, Folder 85)
- California Institute of Technology, 2005-2013 (Box 16, Folder 86)
- Carleton College, 2008-2014 (Box 16, Folder 87)
- Carnegie Mellon University, 2013-2017 (Box 16, Folder 88)
- Case Western Reserve University, 2008-2015 (Box 16, Folder 89)
- College of Notre Dame, 1995-1997 (Box 16, Folder 90)
- College of Notre Dame, 2001-2005 (Box 16, Folder 91)
- College of the Holy Cross, 2008-2015 (Box 17, Folder 92)
- College of Wooster, 2011-2019 (Box 17, Folder 93-94)
- Colorado School of Mines, 2004-2013 (Box 17, Folder 95)
- Columbia University, 2006-2015 (Box 17, Folder 96)
- Computing Research Association, 2008-2016 (Box 17, Folder 97)
- Dartmouth College, 2008-2013 (Box 18, Folder 98)
- Duke University, 2005-2011 (Box 18, Folder 99)
- Duquesne University, 2001-2005 (Box 18, Folder 100)
- Franklin and Marshall College, 2007-2019 (Box 18, Folder 101-102)
- Franklin W. Olin College of Engineering, 2011-2018 (Box 18, Folder 103)
- George Mason University, 2000-2005 (Box 18, Folder 104)
- Gonzaga University, 1999-2009 (Box 18, Folder 105)
- Howard University, 2004-2007 (Box 19, Folder 106)
- Hunter College, 2007-2011 (Box 19, Folder 107)
- Loyola University, Maryland, 2010-2019 (Box 19, Folder 108)
- Loyola University, New Orleans, 2006-2013 (Box 19, Folder 109)
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2006-2013 (Box 19, Folder 110)
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2004-2006 (Box 19, Folder 111)
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1999-2005 (Box 19, Folder 112)
- Michigan Technological University, 2005-2009 (Box 19, Folder 113)
- Morgan State University, 2005-2013 (Box 20, Folder 114)
- Mount St. Mary's University, 2015-2019 (Box 20, Folder 115)
- North Carolina A&T State University, 2006-2013 (Box 20, Folder 116)
- Rice University, 2004-2011 (Box 20, Folder 117)
- St. Mary's College, Indiana, 2011-2017 (Box 20, Folder 118)
- St. Mary's College of California, 2014-2019 (Box 20, Folder 119)
- Seattle University, 2011-2017 (Box 21, Folder 120-121)
- Seattle University, 2001-2013 (Box 21, Folder 122)
- Stanford University, 2001-2007 (Box 21, Folder 123)
- Stonehill College, 2001-2006 (Box 21, Folder 124)
- Stony Brook University, 2004-2013 (Box 21, Folder 125)
- Stevens Institute of Technology, 2006-2013 (Box 21, Folder 126)
- Stevens Institute of Technology, 2003-2013 (Box 21, Folder 127)
- Southeastern Pennsylvania Consortium for Higher Education (SEPCHE), 2013-2019 (Box 22, Folder 128-129)
- Siena College, 1997-2000 (Box 22, Folder 130)
- Skidmore College, 2001-2006 (Box 22, Folder 131)
- Smith College, 2001-2008 (Box 22, Folder 132)
- University of California, Berkeley, 2001-2006 (Box 22, Folder 133)
- University of California, Santa Barbara, 2005-2014 (Box 22, Folder 134)
- University of Chicago, 2006-2011 (Box 22, Folder 135)
- University of Maryland, Baltimore County, 2004-2013 (Box 23, Folder 136)
- University of Massachusetts, 2005-2008 (Box 23, Folder 137)
- University of Richmond, 2006-2013 (Box 23, Folder 138)
- University of San Diego, 2006-2017 (Box 23, Folder 139)
- University of San Diego, 1998-2003 (Box 23, Folder 140)
- University of Virginia, 2008-2016 (Box 23, Folder 141)
- University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2006-2014 (Box 23, Folder 142-143)
- Villanova University, 2011-2019 (Box 24, Folder 144-145)
- Villanova University, 2004-2008 (Box 24, Folder 146)
- Washington College, 2000-2007 (Box 24, Folder 147)
- Xavier University, Ohio, 2004-2013 (Box 24, Folder 148)
- Xavier University of Louisiana, 2013-2017 (Box 24, Folder 149)
- Bucknell University, 2008-2017 (Box 24, Folder 150-151)
- Georgia Institute of Technology, 2012-2016 (Box 25, Folder 152)
- Harvey Mudd College, 2015-2019 (Box 25, Folder 153)
- Harvey Mudd College, 2011-2015 (Box 25, Folder 154)
- Johns Hopkins University, 2012-2016 (Box 25, Folder 155)
- Kalamazoo College, 2010-2014 (Box 25, Folder 156)
- Knox College, 2005-2011 (Box 25, Folder 157)
- Marquette University, 2005-2013 (Box 25, Folder 158)
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2011-2016 (Box 26, Folder 159)
- Mills College, 1996-2022 (Box 26, Folder 160)
- Morgan State University Foundation, 2011-2015 (Box 26, Folder 161)
- Regis University, 2003-2012 (Box 26, Folder 162)
- Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 2005-2008 (Box 26, Folder 163)
- Saint Anselm College, 2008-2012 (Box 26, Folder 164)
- Saint Louis University, 2012-2016 (Box 26, Folder 165)
- Siena College, 2006-2013 (Box 27, Folder 166)
- Smith College, 2010-2017 (Box 27, Folder 167)
- Society of Women Engineers (SWE), 2011-2014 (Box 27, Folder 168)
- Society of Women Engineers (SWE), 2006-2012 (Box 27, Folder 169)
- Society of Women Engineers (SWE), 2003-2012 (Box 27, Folder 170)
- Steven Institute of Technology, 2013-2016 (Box 27, Folder 171)
- Tufts University, 2010-2016 (Box 27, Folder 172)
- University of California, Los Angeles, 2010-2014 (Box 27, Folder 173)
- University of Colorado at Boulder, 2010-2015 (Box 28, Folder 174)
- University of Oregon, 2005-2015 (Box 28, Folder 175)
- University of Texas at Austin, 2005-2014 (Box 28, Folder 176)
- Wellesley College, 2007-2014 (Box 28, Folder 177)
- Wheeling Jesuit University, 1999-2010 (Box 28, Folder 178)
- Xavier University, Ohio, 2011-2016 (Box 28, Folder 179)